Frederic and Eileen Monaghan Whitaker Papers
Frederic Whitaker Papers
1928-2005
Whitaker, Frederic
65 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter (1891-1980). Correspondence, published material, paintings, and sketches.
148750
Biographical History
Frederic Whitaker (1891-1980) was an award-winning American artist and writer on painting and art. Whitaker began his artistic career as a metalsmith, working for Gorham Manufacturing Company and Tiffany & Co. and later founding two companies of his own. However, it was as a watercolorist that he became most famous and when he retired in 1949 he devoted himself full-time to painting. He was also active in the promotion of the arts, particularly painting; he was a member of the National Academy of Design, a Fellow of Britain's Royal Society of Arts, served seven years as president of the American Watercolor Society, and founded Audubon Artists. He received numerous awards and recognitions for his work, and was the author of two books and numerous articles and essays on painting, art, and political topics of the day.
Whitaker's wife Eileen Monaghan (1911-2005) was also a painter of watercolors; though less widely known than her husband, she was an important artist in her own right. The couple married in 1943 and often exhibited their work in joint shows. Eileen was a member of the American Watercolor Society, the recipient of many awards, and in 1978 she became only the second woman to be elected to the National Academy of Design's watercolor division.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frederic and Eileen Monaghan Whitaker Papers is divided into seven series: American Watercolor Society material, Artwork, Correspondence, Eileen Whitaker material, Memorabilia, Printed material, and Writings.
American Watercolor Society (AWS) material contains correspondence, committee information, publications such as newsletters and publicity, the AWS constitution and revisions, meeting minutes, reports, material on special projects undertaken by the AWS, and more. Much of this material dates from Frederic's tenure as president of the Society.
Artwork contains both original artwork and reproductions. Works include sketches, drawings, pencil tracings, and of course watercolors. Included here are some examples of Whitaker's work used in publications, as for example the Prudential Company's annual report.
Correspondence includes both incoming and outgoing correspondence with artists, galleries, publishers,art schools, art organizations, family and friends. Correspondents of note include Walt Disney, Clara Fasano, Boyland Fitzgerald, William Gropper, Jimmy Hatlo, Anna Hyatt Huntington, Janice Lovoos (Whitaker biographer), Edmondo Quattrocchi, and more.
Eileen Whitaker material consists of a small amount of material related solely to Frederic's wife Eileen. This includes awards, biographical material, clippings, and other items.
Memorabilia contains a wide range of items, from address books to souvenir paintbrushes. The bulk of this series consists of photographs taken by the Whitakers both in the United States and other countries, and scrapbooks.
Printed material includes articles, clippings and exhibit catalogs. The majority of the clippings related to either Frederic or Frederic and Eileen, but there is also one folder of clippings related solely to Eileen.
Whitaker's Writings include articles, drafts of his autobiography and an assortment of biographical sketches, essays on a variety of topics (art, beauty, charity, equality, free enterprise, noncitizens/immigrants, tolerance, taxes, prostitution, and many more), and a few other items such as a poem.
Arrangement of the Collection
Within each series, material is arranged alphabetically with the exception of clippings and articles, which are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has the papers of many notable painters, sculptors and cartoonists. Additional Whitaker material may be found in the papers of
Anna Hyatt Huntington
,
Eliot Candee Clark
,
Moissaye Marans
and
Norman Kent
, among others.
Separated Material
A large number of published books and monographs by and about the Whitakers have been removed from the collection and transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. To locate these items, please refer to and search for "Gift of Frederic Whitaker".
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Kent, Norman, 1903-1972.; Lovoos, Janice.; Whitaker, Eileen Monaghan, 1911-; Whitaker, Frederic.; American Artists Professional League.; American Watercolor Society.; Audubon Artists.; Frederick and Eileen Monaghan Whitaker Foundation.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Address books.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Line drawings.; Manuscripts for publication.; Pamphlets.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Watercolors (paintings); Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- American Watercolor Society
  - Arcier Project (Box 1)
  - Awards
    - Data and possibilities, 1952 (Box 1)
    - Letters to donors, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Watercolor of the Year Award, 1951 (Box 1)
  - AWS organizational material
    - Annual Report and Foreword, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Letters to Fred (Pre-Presidency), 1956-1968; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Meeting minutes, 1978-1981; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Newsletters, 1993-2005; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - AWS Annual, 1956 (Box 1)
    - AWS Annual Show, 1951 (Box 1)
    - AWS Expansion, undated (Box 1)
    - AWS Information Center, undated (Box 1)
    - AWS Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Changes for 1953 (Box 2)
  - Cocktail Party Press (Box 2)
  - Committees
    - Advertising, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Associated Members, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Awards, 1955 (Box 2)
    - Catalog, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Catalog Advertisements, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Constitution Revision, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Cultural Relations, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Demonstrations, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Dinner, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Duties (Box 2)
    - Exhibition, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Finance, 1954 (Box 2)
    - Gasser / Grumbacher, undated (Box 2)
    - Gifts and Bequests, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Historian, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
    - Members, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Officers, Addresses, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Olson Awards (Box 2)
    - Personnel of Committees, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Public Relations, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Regional, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Regional Washington (Box 2)
    - Society-Tie Up, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Cooper Spec. meeting (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Allied Artists (Box 2)
    - Arrangements with NAD (Box 2)
    - Awards (Box 2)
    - AWS material, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - Committees (Box 2)
    - Eileen, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Eileen (Kent Day Coes) (Box 3)
    - Gibson Art Company (Box 3)
    - Members (Box 3)
    - Non-Members (Box 3)
    - Officers (Box 3)
    - Secretary (Box 3)
    - Treasurer (Box 3)
    - Walleen (Box 3)
  - Demonstrators (Box 3)
  - Dinner, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Exhibition, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Fund-raising (Box 3)
  - Fund-raising foundations (Box 3)
  - Grand Prize (Box 4)
  - Hague Certificate (Box 4)
  - Information booklet (Box 4)
  - Informative [material]
    - Exhibition Schedule, 1953-1955 (Box 4)
    - Artist Labs (Box 4)
    - Constitution (Box 4)
    - Data (Box 4)
    - Duties of President and Vice President (Box 4)
    - Schedules (Box 4)
    - Voting results, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Invitations to AWS Exhibit (Box 4)
  - Jury of Awards, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Letterhead design (Box 4)
  - Letters
    - Alphaeus Cole protest (Box 4)
    - Art Jury in Action (Box 4)
    - Associated member leaflets (Box 4)
    - AWCS printed forms (Box 4)
    - AWS donor leaflets (Box 4)
    - Biographical questionnaire (Box 4)
    - Membership in AWS (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - President Harry S. Truman (Box 4)
    - President's Report, Feb 1954 (Box 4)
    - President's Report, Aug 1954 (Box 4)
    - To members (Box 4)
    - To new members (Box 4)
    - Various forms (Box 4)
    - Why AWS needs money (Box 4)
  - M.C. (Box 4)
  - Meeting material (Box 4)
  - Mildew on paper (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 4)
  - New donors / Patrons (Box 4)
  - Paper
    - Advertising (Box 4)
    - Agreement (Box 4)
    - Arcier (Box 4)
    - AWS paper advertising (Box 4)
    - Grumbacher endorsement (Box 4)
    - Kornreich insurance (Box 4)
    - Stevens-Nelson Paper Company (Box 4)
  - Plessner picture project (Box 4)
  - Press releases, 1945-1949 (Box 5)
  - Publicity, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Publicity material ideas, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Records
    - AIMS, undated (Box 5)
    - Financial, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - Lena Newcastle, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Letters to speakers, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Meeting material, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Treasury figures, 1954-1958 (Box 5)
  - Reports
    - Minutes, official records, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - National Arts Club dinner, 1950 (Box 5)
    - Speeches to AWS, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
  - Robert Lesch Company, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Special projects
    - AWA, undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Grumbacher, undated (Box 5)
    - History, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Publicity AWCS, undated (Box 5)
    - Reuel, Estill, Co., 1950 (Box 5)
  - The Spanish Institute, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Vital statistics, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Voting data, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Walter White plan, 1952; * (Box 5)
- Artwork
  - Color reproductions (Box 6)
  - Color sketches, 9 folders (Box 6)
  - Drawings for American Watercolor Society (Box 6)
  - Illustrations for articles (Box 6)
  - National Eucharistic Congress, 8th, held in October of 1938 in New Orleans, LA, designs, working drawings, and sketches for ostensorum, candelabra, crucifixes, etc., at various levels of detail (Tube 1)
  - National Eucharistic Congress, 8th, held in October of 1938 in New Orleans, LA, drawings for coats of arms and shields for archdiocese of New Orleans (Oversize 6)
  - Paintings (matted), 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Pencil sketches
    - [General], 4 folders (Box 7)
    - [General] (oversize) (Oversize 1)
    - Church, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Manufactured goods (Box 7)
    - Mexico and Spain (Box 7)
    - Mexico and Spain (cont.) (Box 8)
  - Pencil tracings (Box 8)
  - Photographs of Fred Whitaker [MISSING May 2016], 2 folders
  - Photostats, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Printed miscellanea (Box 8)
  - Prudential
    - Annual report, 1971 (Box 8)
    - Calendar, undated (Box 8)
    - General, 1963; includes b&w photographs of sketches (Box 8)
    - Houston, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Los Angeles, 1964; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Minneapolis, undated (Box 8)
    - Newark, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Toronto, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Watercolors, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Watercolors, 4 folders (Box 9)
  - Watercolor sketches, 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Watercolors, 6 folders (Box 10)
  - Watercolors (matted), 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Watercolors (oversize) (Oversize 2)
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous - A (Box 11)
  - Abrahamsen, Christian, 1958-1974 (Box 11)
  - Academic Artists Association, 1959; 1965-1970,; 1953-1962,; 1958-1960 (Box 11)
  - Abbott, Robert, undated (Box 11)
  - Acevedo, Guillermo, 1968-1972 (Box 11)
  - Acker, Perry, 1965-1974 (Box 11)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1939 (Box 11)
  - Allied Artists of America, 1944-1966; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Allied Publications, Inc., 1962-1967 (Box 11)
  - Amateur Artists Association of America, Inc., 1951-1957 (Box 11)
  - American Art in Sports, Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 11)
  - American Artist, 1943-2004; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - American Artists Group, Inc., 1945 (Box 11)
  - American Artists Professional League, Inc., 1948-1970; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - American Artist Societies, Council of, 1968-1970; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - American Society of Miniature Painters, 1956-1958 (Box 12)
  - American Artist Professional League, 1948 (Box 12)
  - American Veteran's Society of Artists Inc., 1950-1971 (Box 12)
  - America's Artists in Particular, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
  - Anargyros, Spero, 1966-1967 (Box 12)
  - Anderson, Harry, 1958; 1968 (Box 12)
  - Archdiocese of New Orleans, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Architectural League of New York, 1945; 1956 (Box 12)
  - Argent Galleries, 1941 (Box 12)
  - Arizona Highways, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Armory Show, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Arms, John, 1945-1947 (Box 12)
  - Arroyo, Mercedes (Mrs. Nicolas), 1966-1969 (Box 12)
  - Art Association Guild, 1964 (Box 12)
  - Art Association of Newport, 1945 (Box 12)
  - Art Centre of the Oranges, 1945-1959 (Box 12)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 1944 (Box 12)
  - Art League of Long Island, Inc., 1957 (Box 12)
  - The Art Times, 1959-1964 (Box 12)
  - Artist Publishing Company, 1954-1961 (Box 12)
  - Artists and Craftsmen Associated (Dallas, Texas), 1962-1972; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Artists' Fellowship, Inc, 1948-1974 (Box 13)
  - Artists Guild Incorporated, 1941 (Box 13)
  - The Artists Magazine, 1993 (Box 13)
  - Artists U.S.A., 1970 (Box 13)
  - Arts Club of Chicago, 1942-1943 (Box 13)
  - The Arts Centre of Rancho Santa Fe, 1974-1978; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Arvidson, Betsy, 1997-2004 (Box 13)
  - Athenaeum, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Attleboro Museum, Inc., 1950 (Box 13)
  - Audubon Artists, 1965-1980 (Box 13)
  - Avery, Ralph, 1957-1969 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous - B, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Babishvili, Vladimir, undated (Box 13)
  - Baker Gallery, 1978-1982 (Box 13)
  - Baltimore Watercolor Club, 1950-1966 (Box 13)
  - Barnaby, Conrad, 1966-1969 (Box 13)
  - Barnum Festival Art Show, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Barrington Art Show, undated (Box 13)
  - Bartell, George, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Beaugureau-Schimmel Gallery, 1956-1967; undated (Box 13)
  - Bender, Bill, 1972-1973 (Box 14)
  - Bernard & Grunning, 1938; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Betts, Edward, 1968-1969 (Box 14)
  - Blegvad, Eric, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Bockhorst, Paul, 2002-2003 (Box 14)
  - Bohnert, Rosetta, 1955-1956 (Box 14)
  - Boston Arts Festival, 1956 (Box 14)
  - Boston Committee for Fair Representation in Art Exhibitions, 1961 (Box 14)
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Boston Society of Water Color Painters, 1953-1957 (Box 14)
  - Bradshaw Gallery, 1996-1997 (Box 14)
  - Brandon, Warren, 1966-1973 (Box 14)
  - Brandt, Rexford and Joan, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Brewl, Harold, 1943-1964; undated (Box 14)
  - Bridgeport Art League, 1959 (Box 14)
  - Brinker, Aquinas P., 1943-1951 (Box 14)
  - Brommer, Gerald, 1972-2004 (Box 14)
  - Bruggers Fine Arts and Transfer Co., Inc., undated (Box 14)
  - Burr Galleries, 1957-1959 (Box 14)
  - Butler Institute of American Art, 1942-1959 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous - C, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - California Exposition Art Show, 1970-1971 (Box 14)
  - California Watercolor Society, 1949-1968 (Box 14)
  - Campbell, Cameron, 1994-2001 (Box 15)
  - Camelback Galleries, 1949 (Box 15)
  - Campos Photography, 1998-1999 (Box 15)
  - Carnes, Michael and Suzanne, 1986-2003 (Box 15)
  - Carr, Jim Gordon, 1959-1967 (Box 15)
  - Carter, Mary, 1955-1989 (Box 15)
  - Castaňon Custom Frames, 1990-2004 (Box 15)
  - Catherine Lorillard Wolfe Art Club, 1963 (Box 15)
  - Cayuga Museum of History and Art, 1944-1955 (Box 15)
  - Challis Galleries, 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - Chase National Bank, 1949-1960 (Box 15)
  - Chouinard Art Institute, 1956 (Box 15)
  - Checkley, David, 1961-1972 (Box 15)
  - Cianfarani, Aristide B., 1946-1960 (Box 15)
  - Circle Gallery, 1974-1996 (Box 15)
  - Cirino, Antonio, 1965-1977 (Box 15)
  - Clark, Eliot, 1954-1962 (Box 15)
  - Clement, Charles, 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - Close, Frank (Mrs.), 1969-1973 (Box 15)
  - Coes, Kent, 1955-1966 (Box 15)
  - Code of Fair Practice, 1948-1952 (Box 15)
  - Committee for Fair Representation in Art Exhibitions, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Community Art Project, 1942 (Box 15)
  - Conacher Galleries, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Connecticut Academy of Fine Arts, 1957-1958 (Box 15)
  - Connecticut Classic Arts, 1959; 1962 (Box 15)
  - Connecticut Watercolor Society, 1948-1959 (Box 15)
  - Cooper, Mario, 1960-1972 (Box 15)
  - Copenhagen Gallery, 1976 (Box 15)
  - Copley Newspapers, 1974-1984 (Box 15)
  - Corrigan, James, 1952-1959 (Box 15)
  - Council of American Artist Societies
    - [General], 1962-1963 (Box 16)
    - Publicity Releases, undated (Box 16)
    - American Artists Professional League, 1967 (Box 16)
    - Council letterhead, undated (Box 16)
    - Exhibitions, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Informative data, undated (Box 16)
    - Artist/manufacturer relations, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Frank Reilly, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
    - Frank C. Wright, Jr., 1963 (Box 16)
      See also Wright, Frank C. below.
  - Council of Traditional Artists Societies, 1967-1970 (Box 16)
  - Court, Lee Winslow, 1961-1968 (Box 16)
  - Cowboy Hall of Fame, 1973-1975 (Box 16)
  - Cowie Galleries, 1952 (Box 16)
  - Cox, Barbara, 1992-1994 (Box 16)
  - Crafton Hills College, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Creative Club, 1963 (Box 16)
  - Crisp, Arthur, 1956 (Box 16)
  - Currier Gallery of Art, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous - D (Box 16)
  - Daggett, Noel, 1962 (Box 16)
  - Damrosch, Dr. Walter, 1947 (Box 16)
  - Danbury Academy of the Arts, 1963 (Box 16)
  - Dartmoor Artists, 1954 (Box 16)
  - DeHellebranth, Elena M., 1958-1965 (Box 16)
  - DeLue, Donald, 1952-1969 (Box 16)
  - DeMaine, Harry and Lucy, 1942; 1974 (Box 16)
  - Desert-Southwest Art Gallery, 1960-1970 (Box 16)
  - Dictionary of Artists, 1966-1967 (Box 16)
  - Discussions conducted by Frederic Whitaker, 1947-1955 (Box 16)
  - Disney, Walt, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Dixie College, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
  - Dole, John S, 1966-1967 (Box 16)
  - Donald Art Publications, 1944 (Box 16)
  - Douglaston Art League, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Doyle, William and Anita Figueredo, 1967-2003 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous - E (Box 16)
  - Eccles, Albert E. (Mr. and Mrs.), 1960-1973 (Box 16)
  - Edward-Dean Museum of Decorative Arts, 1967-1970 (Box 16)
  - Edwin Austin Abbey Scholarship Fund, See Incorporated Edwin Austin Abbey Memorial Scholarship Fund.
  - Egan, John, 1981 (Box 16)
  - Eighth Street Gallery & Art School, 1942 (Box 16)
  - El Camino Memorial Park, 1980-1995 (Box 17)
  - Eliot O'Hara Watercolor School, 1955 (Box 17)
  - Ellenshaw, Peter, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Ellison, Cy, 1966-1994 (Box 17)
  - Emerson-Bailey, Richard, 1961 (Box 17)
  - Engel, Michael, 1944-1963 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous - F (Box 17)
  - Fabri, Ralph, 1947-1974 (Box 17)
  - Falsone, Jack, 1992; 2002 (Box 17)
  - Famous Artists School, 1950-1962 (Box 17)
  - Faragil Galleries, 1940-1942; 1963 (Box 17)
  - Fasano, Clara, 1957 (Box 17)
  - Feeley, Joe and Velma, 1965-1968 (Box 17)
  - Fifty American Artists, 1953 (Box 17)
  - Fine Arts Collectors Club, Inc., 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - Fine Arts Federation of New York, 1947-1964 (Box 17)
  - Fine Arts Gallery (Society) of San Diego, 1967-1972 (Box 17)
  - Fischer, Frederick, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Fitzgerald, Boyland, 1958-1959 (Box 17)
  - Fleuridas, Andre, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Flint, Russell, 1950 (Box 17)
  - Florida Southern College, 1950-1952 (Box 17)
  - Foster, Will, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Foster, Walter, 1967 (Box 17)
  - Founders Gallery (University of San Diego), 1981-1994 (Box 17)
  - Francis, Emily A. (Contemporary Arts Gallery), 1960 (Box 17)
  - Frank Reilly's School of Art, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Franklin Mint, 1973-1974 (Box 17)
  - Franz, Leslie, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Frohlich, Minnette, 1966-1967; 1982 (Box 17)
  - Frye Museum, 1980-1994 (Box 18)
  - Fuller, Harvey, 1983; 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous - G (Box 18)
  - Gallerias Cortez, 1976 (Box 18)
  - The Gallery of Distinguished Artists, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Gallery of Southwestern Art, 1953-1954 (Box 18)
  - Gammell, R.H. Ives, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Garth, John, 1964-1970 (Box 18)
  - Gasser, Henry, 1946; 1955-1969 (Box 18)
  - Gibson, George, 1970-1992 (Box 18)
  - Glanzman, Louis, 1962 (Box 18)
  - Glicksman, Allen, 1960 (Box 18)
  - Global Advertising Services, Inc., 1965-1966 (Box 18)
  - Gorsline, Douglas, 1964 (Box 18)
  - Gramatky, Hardie, 1959-1968 (Box 18)
  - Gramatky-Smith Family, 1989-2001 (Box 18)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1944-1971 (Box 18)
  - Grant, Gordon, 1941; 1943,; 1954 (Box 18)
  - Graphology, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Greenwich Society of Artists, 1953 (Box 18)
  - Gropper, William, undated (Box 18)
  - Gubing, Ruth, 1966-1970 (Box 18)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1956 (Box 18)
  - Guild of Boston Artists, 1959 (Box 18)
  - Guatemala, 1991-1998 (Box 18)
  - Gute, Herbert J., 1961-1964 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous - H (Box 19)
  - Haddock, Arthur, 1955-1956 (Box 19)
  - Hall of Fame [of American Artists], 1960-1970 (Box 19)
  - Halladay, Allan, 1960-1970 (Box 19)
  - Hammond, A.H. Knighton, 1959-1960 (Box 19)
  - Harbor Art Galleries, 1955 (Box 19)
  - Hardin, Adlai S., 1960 (Box 19)
  - Hartford Society of Women Painters, Inc., 1958 (Box 19)
  - Hartley, Harrison, 1955-1964 (Box 19)
  - Harvey, Gerald (G. Harvey Gallery), 1965 (Box 19)
  - Hassrick, Royal B., 1974 (Box 19)
  - Hatfield Gallery, 1966-1969 (Box 19)
  - Hatlo, Jimmy, 1950 (Box 19)
  - Heitland, Bill, 1949-1962 (Box 19)
  - Henry & Cahill, LLP., 2002 (Box 19)
  - Herman, Vic, 1968-1973 (Box 19)
  - Hermes, Ernest, 1940 (Box 19)
  - Hibiscus Alley, 1949-1950 (Box 19)
  - Hillbom, Henrik, undated (Box 19)
  - Hill, Thomas J., 1958-1971 (Box 19)
  - Hines, Diane C., 1990-1991 (Box 19)
  - Hoban, Russell C., 1961 (Box 19)
  - Hobbelink-Kaastra Art Gallery, 1958 (Box 19)
  - Holden, Donald, 1965 (Box 19)
  - Holly, Harold, 1965-1970 (Box 19)
  - Horatio Alger Award, 1973-1976 (Box 20)
  - Horse Museum, 1957 (Box 20)
  - Houlihan, Raymond F., 1965 (Box 20)
  - Hudson Valley Art Association, 1950-1961 (Box 20)
  - A. Huney Gallery, 1975-1990; 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Hunt, Dr. E. Woodrow, 1953 (Box 20)
  - Huntington, Anna, 1928 (Box 20)
  - Huntingtons, Jon Kery, 1928 (Box 20)
  - Huntington Hartford Foundation, 1963-1965 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous - I (Box 20)
  - Incorporated Edwin Austin Abbey Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1952 (Box 20)
  - International Art Services, Inc., 1988 (Box 20)
  - International Association of Plastic Arts, 1953-1956 (Box 20)
  - International Studio Art Corporation, 1940 (Box 20)
  - Irvington Art and Museum Association, 1952 (Box 20)
  - Isaac Delgado Museum of Art, 1951 (Box 20)
  - Ishikawa, Shinji, 1954-1968 (Box 20)
  - Insurance companies, 1942 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous - J (Box 21)
  - Jambor, Louis, 1945; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Jenckes, Thomas A., 1936-1938 (Box 21)
  - Jennings, Jan, 1975-2005; correspondence, manuscript, Whitaker Foundation correspondence; 3 folders (Box 21)
  - Jones, Franklin, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Jones Gallery, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1958-1961 (Box 21)
  - Jung, Kwan Y. and Yee Wah, 1971-2002; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous - K (Box 21)
  - Kabat, Jack, 1963-1964 (Box 21)
  - Kaep, Louis, 1951-1973 (Box 21)
  - Kalin, Victor B., 1988-2002 (Box 21)
  - Kappa Pi National Honorary Art Fraternity, 1949-1950 (Box 22)
  - Kelly, Deidre, 1991-2003 (Box 22)
  - Kennedy Galleries, Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 22)
  - Kenneth Lynch & Son, Inc., 1941 (Box 22)
  - Kent, Norman, 1960-1971; 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Kery, Jon, 1972-1992; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Kester, Lenard, 1959-1967; 1992 (Box 22)
  - Kinghan, Charles, 1961-1969 (Box 22)
  - Kingman, Dong, undated (Box 22)
  - Kinyon, Robert, See Millsap & Kinyon.
  - Klein, George, 1944-1950; 1972 (Box 22)
  - Knickerbocker Artists, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
  - Koch, John, 1964 (Box 23)
  - Kocherthaler, Mina, 1957-1964 (Box 23)
  - Kohler Art Center, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Kosa, Emil, 1951-1968 (Box 23)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1945-1946 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous - L (Box 23)
  - Lacy, Ernest, 1988 (Box 23)
  - Laguna Beach Art Association, 1960-1967 (Box 23)
  - La Jolla Art Association, 1967 (Box 23)
  - La Jolla Branch, San Diego Public Library, 1996-2003 (Box 23)